☑ ruijialin@gmail.com ८ 7184960737 in ruijialin 🗘 rayjialin

## **ABOUT**

An iOS developer with a background in SAP consulting. I am experienced in creating iOS apps with users in mind, I also understand the importance of creating readable and maintainable source code. And I enjoy reading newsfeeds in the morning to learn about latest iOS news and updates.

## **SKILLS**

LANGUAGES

Swift, Objective-C, C, Ruby, Javascript, HTML, CSS, ABAP

FRAMEWORKS & TESTING TOOLS

Core Animation, Foundation, Core Location, MapKit, AVKit, Parse, Realm, Firebase, Core Data, Cloud Anchor, XCTest,

UIKit, Core Graphics, ARKit

**DESIGN PATTERNS** 

MVC, MVVM, Delegation, KVO

# **PROJECTS**

July 2018 to Current

MultiPeer Selfie

Tech Stack: (Multipeer Connectivity, AVFoundation)

 A selfie taking app that connects multiple iPhones together to act as camera or remote to take selfie using multi-peer connectivity framework

May 2018 to Current

Beer Pong AR

Tech Stack: (Firebase, Cloud Anchor, ARKit, SceneKit, Core Animation)

- A multiplayer AR Beer Pong game that uses ARKit and Scenekit to create beer pong scene, and synchronize game state in realtime using Firebase and Google Cloud Anchor
- · We aimed to make playing beer pong game accessible to anyone and anywhere

May 2018 to Current

HeadsUP

Tech Stack: (Firebase, Core Location, GeoFire, MapKit, User Default)

- The app uses MapKit and Core Location to display user location on the map, GeoFire to detect nearby user within certain radius; and Firebase manages all the connections for each user
- · The purpose of this app is to promote people to meet new friends and talk to people instead of looking down on their phones

# **EDUCATION**

2018 Lighthouse Labs

Immersive iOS Developer Bootcamp 2018

2013 Barn

Barnard Baruch College Computer Information Systems

## **EXPERIENCE**

March 2017 to Sept. 2017

Sompo · SAP Business Analyst · Purchase, NY

Involved in FS-RI and FS-CD implementation from requirement gathering to go live phase

June 2013 to Feb. 2017

Virtusa · SAP Consultant · New York, NY

Client: ADP (06/2016 - 01/2017)

SAP Technical Consultant

- · Worked on Electronic Federal Tax Payment System implementation to help clients to file taxes for their employees
- Configured SAP Gateway to connect with the front end system

Client: CareSource (04/2015 - 05/2016)

SAP Technical Consultant

• Worked on FS-CD implementation to automate their incoming payment process and payment clarification process

Client: United Guarantee (09/2013 - 03/2015)

SAP Techno-Functional Consultant

- Created and performed technical unit testings, user acceptance testings and user security testing for various processes
- · Conducted requirement workshops with business users and project team for billing, payment and disbursement processes